Fight.
Fight!
What are you doing?
Were you just saying, "Fight. Fight,"
to the mirror just now?
Hey. You said, "Fight. Fight," didn't you?
By "Fight. Fight," what are you fighting?
If you're saying, "Fight. Fight,"
does that mean there're two fights?
Keeping quiet isn't helping. Normally,
people don't talk to themselves like that.
I know I've never talked to myself
in the mirror before.
By the way, I think your hair is cool.
When it's all disheveled, it's kinda like
you're hard-working and carefree.
What did you come for?!
What? To talk, of course.
The first time we met,
didn't we talk about Titans all night?
Though you mostly listened
as I blabbered on and on.
I honestly believed that you would
never sacrifice Historia.
"A Sound Argument"
"2 Years Ago"
Eren, I haven't seen you since you
lifted our ship a whole year ago.
I'm honored to work with you.
No, you won't be working together.
You're lucky enough to see his face.
Plenty enough for me.
Today will be a joyous day.
The port is complete and we're
welcoming our first outside visitor.
From Paradis Island's
sole friendly nation, Hizuru--
Special Envoy, Kiyomi Azumabito.
Do you recognize this family crest?
That's...
Show it, Mikasa.
But my mom said to keep it secret.
You showed it to me when we were little.
It's a secret meant for today.
Go on.
Before she died, this symbol was
passed down to me from my mother.
She said I should pass it on to my child.
What an admirable deed!
Over a century ago, the shogun we
Azumabitos descended from had a son.
He was on friendly terms with
King Fritz and often came to Paradis.
After the Great Titan War,
Hizuru was defeated and in disarray.
In the confusion, a child of the
shogunate was left behind on the island.
You're the lost descendant
of our nation's ruler!
You're the hope of Hizuru!
I still don't get what a nation is.
Anyways, now we've got leverage with Hizuru!
What if it's a trap?
I suppose we should ask Yelena's opinion.
No! That's exactly what they want!
One thing is for certain:
The sea has joined us to the world,
but we're still just a child learning to walk.
We should sit quiet and hear
what others have to say.
Hey, why'd you only show Eren that symbol?
Huh?
You've never taken off
your wrist wrap for anyone.
Well, that's...
You seem happy.
I am! You and I were both born
with a heavy burden to bear!
There's nobody else I'd rather rely on!
It's a historic day for both our nations.
Today is only possible thanks to the one
who brought us together, Zeke Jaeger.
After meeting with him in secret,
we agreed to an arrangement
under the condition we were
able to meet Lady Mikasa.
First, please take a look at this.
That's...!
Huh? This is top-secret in Marley,
but you recognize it?
This "omni-directional mobility gear"
is an anti-Titan weapon made in Paradis.
I procured this on my own,
so don't worry. Consider it a gift.
However, to make this work,
it needs a special fuel.
They call it "Iceburst Stone."
It's a unique underground resource
mined only in Paradis.
There should be traces of it inside the weapon.
Zeke Jaeger said if we cooperate with him,
our nation may just helm an industry
that restores it to its former glory.
And yet, he hasn't even
prospected your reserves.
But a resource like that
in this age of modernization
would be worth its weight
in jewels and treasure.
I'm being used as a pretext?
Yelena said the talks would go well
since the Azumabitos are money grubbers.
After all, it's not worth the risk
coming here unless money is involved.
And? What exactly is the arrangement
you have with Zeke Jaeger?
As you know, Zeke Jaeger
has a secret plan in mind.
To achieve it, Hizuru's cooperation is needed.
Here are his three points to protect
Paradis with the rumbling.
The first is a test run of the rumbling--
to release a sample of its power
and show the world its devastation.
Next is Hizuru's cooperation.
Your military must be strengthened
until use of the rumbling isn't necessary.
Lastly, the Founding Titan and a Titan
with royal blood must be passed down.
That's the third point.
Zeke will pass on the Beast Titan
to someone of royal blood.
Until their 13-year term ends,
they must bear as many kids as possible.
Even if weaponry advances,
the rumbling itself is powerful.
Unless we get rid of it, inheriting Titans
will continue for generations to come.
Is it right for us to push this problem on
our descendants to save ourselves now?
Of course not. But...
Very well. I will inherit the Beast Titan.
As long as the rumbling is tied to our survival.
Historia...
After years of getting trampled on,
now we've gotta breed like livestock?
If that's the price of getting to live,
Zeke Jaeger can take
his damn plan and shove it!
It's too dangerous to gamble
on having the rumbling.
We need to spend our time exploring
what other options are available to us.
You should know I felt
the same sense of urgency.
But I still don't get why you went on
your own and put the island in danger.
Don't you care about Historia?
I ate the War Hammer Titan.
Huh?
It has the power to harden through
the ground and make whatever it wants.
In other words, there's no prison
deep or strong enough to hold me.
I can leave whenever I want.
I have the Founding Titan and you can't kill me.
You can't kill Zeke either,
even if you threaten to.
So, Hange... What is it you can actually do?
Tell me, Hange! If you've got something
up your sleeve, let's hear it!
Eren, you perv!
Still in a rebellious phase?! You moron! Idiot!
Erwin, you only made one mistake in your life.
Why did you make me commander?
Come on inside, Historia.
You've gotta take care of your body.
"Hizuru: An eastern nation with its own culture
whose head of state is called a 'shogun.' They
flourished in weapons and aircraft development
and was at one time an Eldian Empire ally."
We should've stuck with our plan
and fed Zeke to Historia as soon
as he got to the island.
Who would've thought?!
She played around and got pregnant!
In the end, she's a low-bred girl
who's Queen in name only.
Hey! Quit it.
The Queen is free to choose a partner.
We've already confirmed the guy
isn't anyone's lackey.
They grew up in the same area.
Back then, he apparently threw rocks
at her trying to get her attention.
He started helping at her
orphanage out of guilt.
He worked with his head down for years,
but the one who approached the other...
...was the Queen.
Who cares about their love story?
The problem is, why did the Queen
decide to get pregnant all of a sudden?!
Someone told her! "If you're pregnant,
they won't make you a Titan!"
I bet it was Yelena. That woman is nuts,
but she's smart enough to be dangerous.
"If the Queen is pregnant,
Zeke lives another day!"
Hey! You're drunk, Roeg.
We should do it anyways.
Make her a Titan, pregnant or not.
Her child might die. And if something
happens to the Queen, it's over.
Giving birth is risky enough as it is.
That sound argument
might just ruin our country!
Hey! Bring another bottle, Marleyan!
Certainly.
Greiz.
Nicolo...
This one, right?
Hey! Is this... something...
they really needed us... to do?!
Nope! We wouldn't be doing this,
but that idiot opened their mouth.
"We can develop the island and
our muscles at the same time," my ass.
We can't do much but wait
for Hizuru's answer anyways.
Yeah. And hope they can be
our mediator to the world.
We're grasping at straws here trying to
avoid the rumbling and save Historia.
--Yeah
--Hey!
Man, you're all working hard in this heat!
Yeah, well, we're stuck watching this idiot.
Unbelievable. You're all growing so damn big.
Is it about Hizuru?
The Azumabitos sent their reply.
And?
No good. Looks like we can't turn to Hizuru.
It seems they want to monopolize
Paradis Island's resources.
They won't help us trade with others.
The world wants Paradis Island
to be the root of all evil.
It helps to unite all nations
and brings stability to the world.
So, we've got no choice but to rely on
the rumbling and sacrifice Historia?
That's right.
You're kidding! They decided we're
devils without knowing our intentions?
Why won't they consider a path of peace?
I think... because they don't know.
They fear us because they
don't know what we are.
That's right. They won't trust people
whose faces they haven't seen.
So let's meet 'em! If you don't
understand something, go figure it out!
Isn't that what we Scouts do?
Make a base in Marley and infiltrate, huh?
Hange sure has a plan for everything.
I'll be able to chow down
on real Marleyan cuisine!
Yeah? What should I bring?
It would stink to get the runs.
Stomach medicine, toothbrush,
a taste of home...
Did you even hear Hange's plan?
If the world knows that we want peace,
maybe something will change.
If only we had more time.
I've got just over five years left.
We're gonna have to decide
who inherits my Titan soon.
I will.
Not you. We still don't know
what the Ackermanns are.
And won't it hurt any plans with Hizuru
if you become a Titan?
No, for so many reasons.
Then who will?
Me. First of all, I'm way smarter than Eren.
Instead of a suicidal maniac,
you'll have a gifted leader who shows
good judgment in all situations.
In other words, me.
I hate getting an Eren hand-me-down,
but who better than me?
Someone that amazing we don't
wanna lose in 13 years, moron.
Huh?!
You should aim to be a regiment leader.
I'll inherit Eren's Titan.
It works out good, right?
Conny...
That's not good at all. You're an idiot.
Eh?
Don't "eh" me. We can't leave such
an important role up to an idiot.
Eh?
Doggone it... I'll inherit it.
I've got combat experience...
I'm someone you can trust...
By process of elimination, it's gotta be me.
You guys...
I dun wanna. I sure dun wanna though.
Wait, huh? Isn't that weird?
What?
Well, you know...
You said an idiot's not fit for the role.
Hmm?
You're more of an idiot than I am,
so you're contradicting yourself.
Huh?
Huh...?
I don't want any of you to inherit it.
Why not?
Because you're important to me.
More than anyone else.
So, I want you to have long lives.
Huh?! What are you turning red for?!
The hell kinda mood is this?!
Sorry.
Jean, it's the sunset.
It's making our faces red.
Oh. Nothing we can do about the sun.
To think Commander Pyxis would go
so far as to detain the volunteers.
Since they and the Scouts are so close,
we weren't told in advance.
Yeah. I'm sure he didn't have much choice.
Until Zeke's intentions are made clear,
it puts us in a real pickle.
And Eren's suddenly aboard Zeke's plan.
Whatever the two of them talked about
is something only they know.
Hey. Did that look like Eren to you guys?
Not me. That wasn't Eren.
If he's made up his mind to side
with his half-brother over us...
If he has, then what?
We've gotta be prepared
to cut him down if necessar--
I won't let you!
Huh?
Are you siding with them, too, Mikasa?
I don't think it'll come to that.
Eren cares about us more than anyone.
You guys should know that.
Maybe that's why he's so hostile
to anyone who isn't one of us.
He cares too much.
That's not it.
No matter how strong you were, the old him
tried to keep you off the front lines.
But he made Armin destroy the port
and pulled you into the fight.
All of us, too. The ones he called important.
I think that's because he trusts us.
If we hadn't gone, he couldn't have done it.
And Sasha wouldn't have died.
Mikasa... When Sasha died, what did Eren do?
Did he cry? Did he regret his actions?
Conny, stop.
He laughed.
What part of it was so funny to him?
What part of Sasha dying?
Explain it to me, Mikasa. Why was Eren laughing?
You know everything about him, right?
We'll talk to Eren. Just me, Mikasa, and him.
We'll find out his goal.
But will it help? What if his goals
are the same as Zeke's?
Now that the military has Titan serum,
we've got options.
You don't mean--!
The option of making someone
we trust into a Titan,
who would then inherit Eren's Founding Titan.
Gabi and Falco escape from prison.
Alone and lost, they receive a helping hand
from a devil they're meant to hate.
Next episode: "Deceiver."